Finding Aid for Amateur Radio Club (University of Michigan) records, 1915-1976
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
Amateur Radio Club (University of Michigan) records 1915-1976
Amateur Radio Club (University of Michigan)
1 linear foot
861153 Bimu N50/2
Amateur radio club comprised of students faculty and staff at the University of Michigan founded in 1909. Constitution, minutes and correspondence, 1930-1956; and radio log books, 1915-1976 (scattered dates).
Bentley Historical Library, University of Michigan
The records came to the library in 1983 through David Norden (Donor no. 6881 )
Periodic additions to the records expected.
The Amateur Rdio Club records are open for research without restriction.
The University of Michigan Amateur Radio Club was formed in 1909, one of the first college clubs in the country. Members included students, faculty and staff interested in amateur short-wave or "ham" radio. It was assigned the callsign 8XA. The callsign was changed several times over the years, finally settling as W8UM, which was obtained from the FCC in conjunction with the university sesquicentennial in 1967.
The club remains active and operates Amateur Radio Station W8UM from the fourth floor of the Electrical Engineering and Electronics Building. A tower supports a wide variety of transmit and receive antennas Wes completed on top of the EECS building in July 2007. Current activities and information about the club are available at http://www.umich.edu/~umarc/ (as of September 2008).
The Amateur Radio Club records consist of largely of station log books recording contacts from around the world and various club records, 1930-1956, including the club constitution and minutes.
Subjects:
Radio broadcasting--Michigan--Ann Arbor.; University of Michigan--Students--Societies, etc.; Amateur Radio Club (University of Michigan)
- Club Records
  - Club Records, 1930-1956 (Box 1)
  - Greenland Traffic Message Book, 1928
  - Radiograms, 1928-1929
  - Station Logs
    - 8XA, 1915
    - 8AXZ, 1927-1930
    - W8AXZ, 1932-1941, 9 volumes
    - W8ZUP, 1947
    - W8UM, 1967-1976, 24 volumes
  - Amplifier, ca. 1939-1941
  - Wiring Diagram, 1937